Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine and today we're talking about something we talk about every
我是Catherine，今天我们聊一个我们每年都会
year.
聊的话题。
Every year after Christmas or well during the Christmas holidays, we talk about New
每年圣诞节后，或者说在圣诞假期期间，我们都会聊到新年、
Years, New Years Day and a very important topic, New Years Resolutions.
元旦，还有一个非常重要的话题——新年决心。
Alright, so we're not going to preview anything today.
好的，今天我们就不做任何预告了。
It's all in the dialogue but when we come back, we'll be talking more about what you
所有内容都在对话里，但等我们回来之后，我们会进一步讨论你听到的内容，
hear and some of the great phrases you can use at the New Year.
以及一些你可以在新年用到的很棒短语。
Did you read this?
你读过这个吗？
It says that the number one New Year resolution people make is to spend more time with friends
上面说人们最常做的新年决心是花更多时间与朋友
and family.
和家人在一起。
Why would that be funny?
这有什么好笑的？
Well think about it.
嗯，想想看。
We are a society that is always on the go.
我们是一个总是忙忙碌碌的社会。
Not because we have to but because we want to.
不是因为我们不得不这样，而是因为我们想这样。
Why?
为什么？
We work hard and spend less time at home because we are trying to provide for our family with
我们努力工作，花更少时间在家，因为我们想用通常
goods and services that are usually unnecessary.
不必要的商品和服务来供养家人。
I don't agree but anyways, I think you should start thinking of a New Year's resolution
我不同意，但不管怎样，我觉得你应该开始为自己想一个新年决心
yourself.
了。
What's the point?
有什么意义呢？
We always make New Year's resolutions and by February, we will have forgotten about
我们总是定新年决心，但到了二月，我们就会把它们
them.
忘得一干二净。
It's pointless.
这毫无意义。
Well maybe then you should resolve to sticking to your goals and objectives.
嗯，那也许你应该下定决心坚持你的目标和目的。
What about you?
那你呢？
Your gym bag is gathering dust and you still have brand new running shoes that are yet
你的健身包都积灰了，你还有全新的跑鞋
to be jogged in.
还没穿过跑步呢。
Well I would go if you kept your promise of going to the gym with me every day.
嗯，如果你遵守承诺每天陪我去健身房，我就会去。
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
是啊，是啊，随便吧。
Alright, great, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So this is very typical.
所以这非常典型。
A New Year's resolution that you make but then people don't really stick to it, etc.
你定了一个新年决心，但人们通常不会坚持执行，等等。
They don't?
他们不会吗？
Usually they don't.
通常不会。
Alright, but you're probably wondering what is a New Year's resolution so why don't
好的，但你大概想知道什么是新年决心，所以我们不如
we take a look at this word and many more on Language Takeaway.
在“语言小贴士”环节看看这个词以及更多内容。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Okay, so New Year's resolution, let's break this phrase down.
好的，新年决心，我们来分解一下这个短语。
The first phrase is New Year's.
第一个短语是“New Year's”。
So the New Year is January 1st in the West and it is celebrated on the 31st of December
在西方，新年是1月1日，人们在12月31日晚上庆祝，
at night when the clock changes to the New Year and a New Year's resolution, remember
当时钟跨入新年，而新年决心，记住那个S，
that S there, is something that you want to do or to change in the New Year.
是你在新年想要做或改变的事情。
It's a fresh start.
这是一个全新的开始。
Okay, so you pretty much, the verb that you use there is to resolve to do something.
好的，所以你基本上用的动词是“resolve to do something”。
So my New Year's resolution is to go to the gym every day.
所以我的新年决心是每天去健身房。
It's like a promise to yourself.
这就像对自己许下的承诺。
Right, so and this is very common right among Americans.
对，这在美国人中非常普遍。
They try and because it's a New Year, it's a fresh start so they want to start doing
他们尝试，因为这是新年，是一个全新的开始，所以他们想开始做
something great.
一些很棒的事情。
Exactly, we can talk about this at the end but a lot of companies try to use this to
没错，我们可以在最后讨论这个，但很多公司试图利用这个
sell Americans stupid things so we'll get there in a minute.
向美国人推销愚蠢的东西，我们一会儿会说到。
But the two people in this dialogue are talking about the idea of spending more time with
但对话中的两个人在讨论花更多时间与朋友
friends and family.
和家人在一起的想法。
And the other person says, well sometimes it's hard to do that because you have to provide
另一个人说，嗯，有时候很难做到，因为你必须用
your family with goods and services.
商品和服务来供养家人。
This phrase goods and services is very common especially in economics and sociology.
“商品和服务”这个短语非常常见，尤其是在经济学和社会学中。
So what does this mean?
那这是什么意思呢？
And they go together, right?
它们是一起出现的，对吧？
So goods are tangible items, things that you buy, you know like food or you know clothes,
所以商品是有形的物品，你买的东西，比如食物、衣服、
a TV, etc.
电视等等。
Stuff.
东西。
And services of course are other things like for example going to the doctor or the dentist
而服务当然是其他东西，比如去看医生或牙医，
or any other service you get.
或者你得到的任何其他服务。
So service usually includes another person doing something for you.
所以服务通常包括另一个人为你做某事。
But you might not actually get something physical like a TV if you pay for it.
但你可能不会实际得到像电视这样的实物，如果你付钱的话。
So goods and services, it's included in this phrase always goods and services.
所以商品和服务，这个短语总是“goods and services”。
Very good.
非常好。
And well moving on as we mentioned with the New Year's resolution, we had that verb there,
然后继续，正如我们提到新年决心时，我们用了那个动词，
to resolve.
“resolve”。
So what does it mean if I want to resolve?
所以如果我想“resolve”，它是什么意思？
Okay well to resolve as we said is to decide or to promise yourself to do something.
好的，“resolve”就像我们说的，是决定或向自己承诺做某事。
So it's a decision that you don't want to change your mind about.
所以这是一个你不想改变主意的决定。
For example, I, this year, I've resolved to quit smoking.
比如，我今年决心戒烟。
That means I've made a decision for myself and I'm going to do it.
这意味着我为自己做了决定，并且我会去做。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
It's very strong.
这语气很强。
And not to be confused with like to solve, right?
而且不要和“solve”混淆，对吧？
It has no real relation there, right?
它们之间没有实际关联，对吧？
No, resolve, to resolve to do something is to have a strong passion or interest in doing
不，“resolve to do something”是对为自己做某事或改变行为
something for yourself or changing an action.
有强烈的热情或兴趣。
Very good.
非常好。
And well our last word for language takeaway is brand new.
然后我们“语言小贴士”的最后一个词是“brand new”。
A brand new, something that's brand new.
“brand new”，某样东西是全新的。
Brand new, so buy a brand new car.
“brand new”，比如买一辆全新的车。
Come down to Captain's car lot.
来Captain的汽车销售场吧。
So brand new is something we hear a lot in marketing.
所以“brand new”是我们在营销中经常听到的。
It's also something that, well these words just go together very often.
它也是这些词经常一起出现的情况。
And something is new, okay, you just bought it or it just came out.
某样东西是新的，好吧，你刚买了它或者它刚出来。
But something that's brand new is really fresh, really new.
但“brand new”的东西是非常新鲜、非常新的。
So brand new, a brand new car, a brand new watch, etc.
所以“brand new”，一辆全新的车，一块全新的手表，等等。
A brand new movie.
一部全新的电影。
A brand new movie or brand new cereal.
一部全新的电影或全新的麦片。
Have you ever tried it?
你尝过吗？
Very good.
非常好。
So great phrases there.
所以这些是很棒的短语。
Very good.
非常好。
So great words there.
所以这些是很棒的词汇。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with three phrases.
我们为什么不重新听一遍对话，然后我们会回来讲三个短语。
Did you read this?
你读过这个吗？
It says that the number one New Year resolution people make is to spend more time with friends
上面说人们最常做的新年决心是花更多时间与朋友
and family.
和家人在一起。
Why would that be funny?
这有什么好笑的？
Well think about it.
嗯，想想看。
We are a society that is always on the go.
我们是一个总是忙忙碌碌的社会。
Not because we have to, but because we want to.
不是因为我们不得不这样，而是因为我们想这样。
Why?
为什么？
We work hard and spend less time at home because we are trying to provide for our family with
我们努力工作，花更少时间在家，因为我们想用通常
goods and services that are usually unnecessary.
不必要的商品和服务来供养家人。
I don't agree, but anyways, I think you should start thinking of a New Year's resolution
我不同意，但不管怎样，我觉得你应该开始为自己想一个新年决心
yourself.
了。
What's the point?
有什么意义呢？
We always make New Year's resolutions and by February we will have forgotten about them.
我们总是定新年决心，但到了二月，我们就会把它们忘得一干二净。
It's pointless.
这毫无意义。
Well maybe then you should resolve to sticking to your goals and objectives.
嗯，那也许你应该下定决心坚持你的目标和目的。
What about you?
那你呢？
Your gym bag is gathering dust and you still have brand new running shoes that are yet
你的健身包都积灰了，你还有全新的跑鞋
to be jogged in.
还没穿过跑步呢。
Well I would go if you kept your promise of going to the gym with me every day.
如果你遵守承诺每天和我去健身房，我就会去。
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
行行，随便吧。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at these three phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看“流利度构建器”上的这三个短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay, this first phrase is very common at gas stations and fast food chains.
好的，第一个短语在加油站和快餐连锁店很常见。
We say on the go.
我们说“on the go”。
Alright, so he mentioned that we are a society that is always on the go.
好的，他提到我们是一个总是“on the go”的社会。
It means we're always moving.
意思是我们在不停地移动。
Exactly, so you're always going to work, going home from work, going to the store, going
没错，所以你总是去上班、下班回家、去商店、去
to the school to get the kids.
学校接孩子。
Always moving, moving, moving.
总是在动，动，动。
So that kind of action, that kind of life is on the go.
所以那种行动、那种生活就是“on the go”。
You can also say eat on the go.
你也可以说“eat on the go”。
That means I eat while I'm going somewhere, while I'm doing something.
意思是我在去某个地方或做某事的时候吃饭。
I don't sit down.
我不坐下来吃。
Okay, so on the go.
好的，所以是“on the go”。
And well, talking about New Year's resolution and we said that well many people resolve
说到新年决心，我们提到很多人决心
to do something but they don't really do it.
做某事，但并没有真正去做。
And we have a phrase that is used here, to stick to something.
这里有一个短语，“to stick to something”。
Stick to your resolution.
坚持你的决心。
To stick to it.
坚持下去。
So you think of tape or glue, these things that help things stick together.
你可以想象胶带或胶水，这些东西帮助东西粘在一起。
Okay, so in that sense it's kind of a way for you to describe continuing to do something
好的，所以从这个意义上说，这是一种描述你继续做某事
or not stopping, not quitting, not ending it.
或不停止、不放弃、不结束的方式。
And so I could say, remember how I said I wanted to quit smoking?
所以我可以这样说，还记得我说过我想戒烟吗？
Well I'm really going to stick to this resolution because I think it's important.
我真的会坚持这个决心，因为我觉得这很重要。
That means I'm not going to give up.
意思是我不打算放弃。
Right, very good.
对，很好。
So you're going to stay with it.
所以你会坚持下去。
You're not going to give up.
你不会放弃。
Alright, so stick to something like for example our English learners, they'll stick to learning
好的，所以“stick to something”，比如我们的英语学习者，他们会坚持学习
English.
英语。
And we could say as words of encouragement, hey stick to it.
我们可以作为鼓励的话说，嘿，坚持下去。
Stick to it.
坚持下去。
Don't give up.
不要放弃。
Keep with it.
继续努力。
Don't give up.
不要放弃。
And well finally they were discussing, more arguing about the gym membership and everything
最后，他们在讨论，更多的是争论关于健身房会员的事，
and he mentioned that the gym bag is gathering dust.
他提到健身包在积灰。
Alright, this is a very nice phrase I think because it's very visual.
好吧，我觉得这个短语很棒，因为它很形象。
I like phrases where you can see what's happening.
我喜欢那些能让人看到画面感的短语。
So gathering means collecting.
所以“gathering”就是“收集”的意思。
That means that the dust in the air, it's building on this bag.
这意味着空气中的灰尘正在这个包上堆积。
And something is gathering dust if we don't use it.
如果某样东西我们不用，它就会积灰。
So we haven't gone to the gym because our bag is in the corner and it's just filled
所以我们没去健身房，因为我们的包放在角落里，已经积满了
with dust.
灰尘。
Exactly.
没错。
We could also say this about the computer.
我们也可以这么说电脑。
Why should I buy you a new computer Marco if you never use the old one?
马可，如果你从来不用旧电脑，我为什么要给你买新的？
That's just sitting in the house gathering dust.
那台电脑就放在家里积灰。
Very good.
非常好。
Okay, so it's another way of saying you never use it, you never do it, etc.
好的，所以这是另一种说法，表示你从不使用它，从不做它等等。
It's for an object though.
不过这是针对物品的。
You can't say you are gathering dust.
你不能说“你在积灰”。
No, well that would be a little weird.
不，那会有点奇怪。
You might be dead or something.
你可能已经死了或者什么的。
Alright, great phrases.
好的，很棒的短语。
So why don't we listen to this dialogue one last time.
那我们最后再听一遍这段对话吧。
Did you read this?
你读过这个吗？
It says that the number one New Year resolution people make is to spend more time with friends
上面说人们最常做的新年决心是花更多时间与朋友
and family.
和家人在一起。
Why would that be funny?
那为什么会好笑呢？
Well think about it.
嗯，想想看。
We are a society that is always on the go.
我们是一个总是忙忙碌碌的社会。
Not because we have to, but because we want to.
不是因为我们不得不这样，而是因为我们想这样。
Why?
为什么？
We work hard and spend less time at home because we are trying to provide for our family with
我们努力工作，花更少时间在家，因为我们试图用通常不必要的
goods and services that are usually unnecessary.
商品和服务来供养家人。
I don't agree, but anyways, I think you should start thinking of a New Year's resolution
我不同意，但不管怎样，我觉得你应该开始为自己想一个新年决心
yourself.
了。
What's the point?
有什么意义呢？
We always make New Year's resolutions, and by February we will have forgotten about them.
我们总是制定新年决心，但到了二月就会忘掉。
It's pointless.
这毫无意义。
Well maybe then you should resolve to sticking to your goals and objectives.
嗯，也许你应该下定决心坚持你的目标和目的。
What about you?
那你呢？
Your gym bag is gathering dust and you still have brand new running shoes that are yet
你的健身包在积灰，你还有全新的跑鞋
to be jogged in.
还没穿过呢。
Well I would go if you kept your promise of going to the gym with me every day.
嗯，如果你遵守承诺每天和我一起去健身房，我就会去。
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
是啊，是啊，随便吧。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
And well, as you mentioned, there are some interesting things about this dialogue, especially
嗯，就像你提到的，这段对话里有些有趣的地方，尤其是
when they talked about a society that is always on the go.
当他们谈到一个总是忙忙碌碌的社会时。
And you mentioned that well, sometimes you eat on the go.
你提到，有时候你会边赶路边吃饭。
And I've seen people in the United States that are actually eating while driving.
我在美国见过有人真的边开车边吃东西。
I'm guilty of doing that.
我也干过这种事。
Yeah, you have no time to actually sit down for like 15 minutes and eat.
是啊，你根本没时间坐下来哪怕吃15分钟饭。
No, I remember being in high school at home and you just have so much stuff to do.
不，我记得在家上高中时，事情多得做不完。
You have school, then after school there's like soccer practice, after that there's music
你要上学，放学后还有足球训练，之后还有音乐
lessons and you never have time to eat so you have to grab food in the car and then
课，根本没时间吃饭，所以只能在车里抓点吃的，然后
on the way home you're picking things up and you get home and you do your homework or whatever.
回家路上还要拿东西，到家后做作业什么的。
There's so much stuff to do and it doesn't stop.
事情太多了，根本停不下来。
It doesn't stop when you grow up.
长大以后也停不下来。
It doesn't stop if you're an older person.
年纪大了也停不下来。
That's the way life is in America.
这就是美国的生活方式。
Wow, yeah, that's really interesting because I think many of our listeners that are in
哇，是啊，这真的很有意思，因为我觉得我们很多在
other countries would find that a little bit peculiar if they actually went to the United
其他国家的听众，如果真去美国看到有人在车里
States and saw somebody in their car, you know, like having a hamburger while driving,
一边开车一边吃汉堡，还
you know, and sipping on their soda.
喝着汽水，会觉得有点奇怪。
Yeah, it's kind of sad.
是啊，有点可悲。
Well, that's the thing.
嗯，问题就在这里。
You don't have much time.
你没多少时间。
But actually, this is based on true events, kind of, on the fact that many Americans do
但实际上，这基于真实情况，有点像是很多美国人确实
want to spend more time at home with their friends, with their family because, as you
想花更多时间在家陪朋友和家人，因为就像你
say, you're always so busy.
说的，你总是那么忙。
And I think it's a nice resolution to resolve to have dinner with your family once or twice
我觉得定个新年决心，每周在家和家人吃一两次晚餐，
a week at home where you sit down and you talk about your lives.
坐下来聊聊各自的生活，是个不错的主意。
It's nice because you get to share and you get to know each other better and, you know,
这很好，因为你们可以分享，更了解彼此，而且，
otherwise you're always just on the go in different places.
否则你总是到处奔波。
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
So we want to hear your comments and your opinions about this topic so why don't you
所以我们想听听你们对这个话题的评论和看法，不如
visit our website EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there.
访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，我们在那里见。
Don't forget to share with us your New Year's resolutions.
别忘了和我们分享你的新年决心。
Everyone's got one.
每个人都有。
So I'm very excited to hear those.
我很期待听到这些。
All right.
好了。
Until next time, everyone.
下次再见，各位。
Bye.
再见。
Happy New Year.
新年快乐。